## Effi Emmanuel

(+234) 8118412819 • Lagos, NG • <u>effiemmanuel.n@gmail.com</u> <u>Github Profile • Linkedin • Twitter</u>

#### **Portfolio Website**

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY / ABOUT ME

I am 19 years old and I'm a Fullstack Javascript web developer with close to 3 years of experience now, building beautiful Web user interfaces, secure and user centric web solutions. I consider myself to be a problem solver and a critical thinker. I enjoy being challenged to build stuff.

I love learning about new technologies and even new programming languages / environments. I have a strong interest in blockchain development, solidity and Fullstack Web3 development. Apart from being a developer, I love playing the piano.

#### **SKILLS**

#### **Frontend**

HTML | CSS | Javascript | APIs | Bootstrap | React | Figma | UI Design

#### **Backend**

Nodejs | Express | MongoDB | REST | Git | GitHub | | PHP | SQL | MySQL

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**Fullstack Web Developer, React, Nodejs** April. 2021 - Present

Pari Technologies India | Remote (HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, Bootstrap, Nodejs, MongoDB, REST APIs)

- Pari Technologies India is a web development agency located in India with over 50 employees.
- I work mostly as a backend developer and I build RESTful APIs here at Pari Technologies as well as consuming APIs built by me or a team mate.
- As a developer here, I get to work on different kinds of projects which require the use of different web technologies. I love this because it pushes me to learn more and more as a developer.
- I also build web applications in React here at Pari Technologies

**Fullstack Web Developer Intern** April. 2021 - Present The Code Center | Lagos, NG (HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, Bootstrap, Nodejs, MongoDB, PHP and MySQL)

- As an intern, my supervisor always talked about my creativity, attention to detail and problem solving skills. I was made the team lead on a couple projects where I got to coordinate all operations in a project from scratch. From the UI design, to the frontend development, the backend development and as well as teaching other interns who were under me at the time as the team lead.
- As an intern, I occasionally worked solely as both a frontend developer (React, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap and JavaScript) and as a backend developer (Nodejs)
- Collaborated with the UI Design team and other developers in my team as well in evaluating, analyzing and building beautiful and efficient web applications.
- Evaluated large code bases to fix bugs and implement new features to existing websites and web applications.

#### Freelance Web Developer

Jan 2020 - Jan 2022

Fiverr inc | Remote

- Built websites and web applications for different clients from Sweden, South Africa, India, the United States and the United Kingdom
- Increased SEO for certain client websites by 10% to as much as 40% by implementing different metadata in their codebase, temporarily helping them manage and upload relevant content regularly, and so on.
- Expanded my personal income by more than 300% from when I started .

#### **President, Tech Cub**

Aug. 2018 - Aug. 2019

Saint Raphael's High School | Lagos, NG

Facilitated the day-to-day operations of the club including practicals, hands-on learning, as well as technical support to 70+ students.

Key Responsibilities: Technical support, teaching and mentoring students in science and technology, giving weekly motivation to students in my club, accountability to my club's head teacher.

- Learned about complex topics and simplified it for students to easily grasp through the use of fun practicals
- Planned with my team to organize a web development coding bootcamp but most students did not have the facilities to go through with it.

#### **PERSONAL PROJECTS**

#### 1. Realtime Chat Application (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, AJAX, PHP, SQL, MySQL) - view here

- a. A real-time chat application.
- b. I plan on pushing updates to this project in order to make it a React app.

#### 2. React Book store (React, Nodejs, Expressjs, MongoDB) - view here

a. This is a fully functional book store app I built using the MERN stack. I have plans to turn this into a Web3 project!

#### 3. Secure Form (Javascript, React, Nodejs, Expressjs, MongoDB) - view here

a. This project makes it possible for a secure communication between the frontend and the backend. Normally, when form details are submitted or sent to the server from the frontend (be it passwords or credit card info), it gets shown on the network tab in the developer tools. The payload is open and literally anyone can have access to one's details. So basically, what this project is all about is Taking the form details, encrypting it and sending the encrypted payload to the server. And also on the reverse, from the server to the frontend.

#### 4. FatApe Club NFT Web Application (Javascript, React) - view here

a. This is a web application I built for a client through Fiverr. I was given a brief to clone the famous <a href="https://fatapeclub.io">https://fatapeclub.io</a> and I did just that and he was so satisfied and I'm happy I received a 5 star rating on this job.

#### 5. NFT Minting Page (Javascript, React) - view here

- a. This is a simple NFT minting page.
- 6. Diesel Refill Website (JavaScript, Nodeis, Express) view here.

#### **EDUCATION**

### Babcock University | Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering

• GPA: 4.178

# **Saint Raphael's High School** | High School Degree • *President*, Tech Club

Expected July. 2023

Graduated August. 2019